<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSO on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/sso/</link><description>Recent content in SSO on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/sso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying NoMAD over VMware Per-App Tunnel</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/deploying-nomad-over-vmware-per-app-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/deploying-nomad-over-vmware-per-app-tunnel/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some folks recently reached out to me asking for help figuring out how to route &lt;a href="https://nomad.menu/support/">NoMAD&lt;/a> traffic over VMware Tunnel. Basically, the ask was to use Per-App Tunneling to give NoMAD the ability to obtain Kerberos Tickets and Sync AD passwords without being directly on the Enterprise network. If you're familiar with my previous article about the &lt;a href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn-followup/">macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO Plugin&lt;/a>, you'll know that Apple's built-in functionality in Catalina doesn't work well with Per-App Tunneling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>macOS Big Sur and Kerberos SSO via Per-App Tunnel</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/macos-bigsur-kerberos-sso-over-vpn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/macos-bigsur-kerberos-sso-over-vpn/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you've read my blogs about &lt;a href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macOS-Catalina-Kerberos-SSO-Over-VPN/">macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO over Per-App Tunnel&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn-followup/">followup&lt;/a>, you'll know that this has been a use-case I'm interested in solving. I put a great deal of effort into filing feedback with Apple and providing steps to replicate the issue. I was quite excited when I saw the per-app Tunnel improvements specifically mentioned in the WWDC videos, and hoped perhaps some changes were made to enable this functionality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO over VPN Followup</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn-followup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn-followup/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I've been going back and forth with Apple about some of the issues I previously found using the &lt;a href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macOS-Catalina-Kerberos-SSO-Over-VPN/">macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO over Per-App VPN&lt;/a>. As it turns out, they acknowledged some of the issues I was seeing and are &lt;em>supposedly&lt;/em> working on a fix. I've been watching the past few beta releases for macOS, and I've not yet seen anything in the release notes to indicate they've implemented any fixes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO Extension Over VPN</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macOS-Catalina-Kerberos-SSO-Over-VPN/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macOS-Catalina-Kerberos-SSO-Over-VPN/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Working at VMware, I'm surrounded by great technology and super-smart folks! In our portfolio of technologies, the folks in our R&amp;amp;D have recently been putting quite a bit of effort into building out macOS capabilities for our Workspace ONE Tunnel client for macOS. Workspace ONE admins can leverage the same VMware technology they used to enable per-app VPN for iOS and Android, but now on macOS! There's a bit of nuance to configuring the VPN client if you're previously familiar with iOS (look for my Operational Tutorial soon to hit &lt;a href="https://techzone.vmware.com">TechZone&lt;/a>). That said, the premise is the same -- by configuring the appropriate rules, the Tunnel app redirects traffic from whitelisted applications back into your network through the Unified Access Gateway.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>