<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updated GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</guid><description>When I restarted my blogging journey last year, I went with Hugo to generate a static website hosted as a GitHub Pages site. As mentioned, Blogger and WordPress always suffered recurring problems, and maintenance with WordPress still turned into a time suck due to its complexity. By comparison, GitHub has been a nearly painless hosting provider, and the way I&amp;rsquo;ve configured it has allowed me to keep drafts hidden by staging in a private repository.</description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</guid><description>I restarted my blogging journey earlier this year when I started looking into Jekyll Hugo to generate a static website. I had past experience with Blogger and Wordpress, but frankly had periodic problems with both platforms that ended up being a time suck. As it has been, Hugo has been a simplistic publishing method and GitHub a reliable (and FREE) hosting provider. Yet, my desire to keep my drafts private (.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Hugo (from Jekyll)</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</guid><description>Welcome to my wholly reworked website! This time, I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped the complexity of Wordpress and opted for something significantly simpler: Jekyll Hugo and GitHub.
Having now hosted the site in GitHub Pages, here was the process I started with Hugo:
Created the Github Pages repo (rterakedis.github.io) &amp;ndash; this is where github pages looks for the blog&amp;rsquo;s generated site files. Created a 2nd Github repo: rterakedis.github.io.hugo &amp;ndash; this repo holds the source files for Hugo to parse and generate the site.</description></item></channel></rss>