<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terminal on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/terminal/</link><description>Recent content in Terminal on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modify ZShell Defaults in macOS</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/modify-zshell-defaults/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/modify-zshell-defaults/</guid><description>
Background I'm finding myself using the Terminal quite a bit more in my job. I spent a few minutes over the past few days looking at different ways to make the default terminal layout in macOS better. While there are many plugins out there for doing this (Oh-My-Zsh), I wanted to do something a little more straightforward.
How You Change zsh Default Layouts Armin Briegel has a great article about customizing the zsh prompt in his moving to zsh series.</description></item><item><title>New Key Added to SoftwareUpdate Command in macOS</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/new-key-added-softwareupdate-command-macos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/new-key-added-softwareupdate-command-macos/</guid><description>
Background When Big Sur released, I noticed an issue trying to discover what macOS versions were available in SoftwareUpdate. I worked around this by using the installinstallmacos.py script to download full installers from the store. This script/tool is solid, but I was really hoping to be able to just do the updates using softwareupdate. Awhile back I filed feedback with Apple to the following:
The --fetch-full-installer parameter for the softwareupdate command line tool is awesome, but there's currently no way to discover the list of available values for the --full-installer-version parameter.</description></item></channel></rss>