<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:24:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Change From Beautifulhugo to Clarity Theme</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/change-from-beautifulhugo-to-clarity-theme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:24:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/change-from-beautifulhugo-to-clarity-theme/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since I first started this blog, I was using a theme called &lt;a href="https://github.com/halogenica/beautifulhugo">BeautifulHugo&lt;/a>. The theme was great and for the most part visually appealing. However, there were some changes I was hoping to see made to the theme that never really manifested. I had even contributed back some of my own changes, but it appeared the theme had been abandoned by it's creator. I set about looking for a new theme and stumbled onto &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipzoller/hugo-clarity">hugo-clarity&lt;/a>. Not only was this theme visually appealing to me, but I could see regular changes being made to the theme. Yes, a theme still under active maintenance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Great *Free* Resources to Learn GitHub</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/great-free-resources-to-learn-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/great-free-resources-to-learn-github/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Source control used to be a scary, odd thing for me back in college and early in my career. Branching, merging, commits... all the buzzwords I remember from my early days dealing with Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS) and Subversion. Admittedly, I never felt like I spent the time required to understand how it all worked. Fast forward to mid-2017, when a group of us within VMware needed to share some of our tips and tricks with the broader VMware community. The &lt;a href="https://github.com/vmware-samples/euc-samples">EUC-Samples&lt;/a> repository was born on GitHub, and my journey like Alice down the rabbit hole began. Over the years, as we've encouraged participation and knowledge sharing amongst those within the community, I still see a hesitation to learn git/GitHub and contribute to the repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updated GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="background">Background&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When I restarted my blogging journey last year, I went with Hugo to generate a static website hosted as a GitHub Pages site. As mentioned, Blogger and WordPress always suffered recurring problems, and maintenance with WordPress still turned into a time suck due to its complexity. By comparison, GitHub has been a nearly painless hosting provider, and the way I've configured it has allowed me to keep drafts hidden by staging in a private repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I restarted my blogging journey earlier this year when I started looking into &lt;del>Jekyll&lt;/del> Hugo to generate a static website. I had past experience with Blogger and Wordpress, but frankly had periodic problems with both platforms that ended up being a time suck. As it has been, Hugo has been a simplistic publishing method and GitHub a reliable (and FREE) hosting provider. Yet, my desire to keep my drafts private (.e.g the use of 2 separate repositories) has created a small overhead in that I have to build and manually commit the website changes to the public repository to make them live.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another GitHub Actions Update - Using Deploy Keys Instead Of Personal Access Tokens</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/another-github-actions-update-change-hugo-publish-deploy-keys/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/another-github-actions-update-change-hugo-publish-deploy-keys/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I restarted my blogging journey in 2020, I switched from Jekyll to Hugo hosted in GitHub pages. It's been a relatively painless journey, and kudos to GitHub as a rock-solid hosting provider. I've covered it before (&lt;a href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/">Initial Setup&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/">First Update&lt;/a>), but I've been incredibly happy with private-to-public publishing workflow that allows me to keep drafts and work-in-progress hidden. That said, a recent comment gave me reason to make another update to the Workflow. Read on for more detail...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to Hugo (from Jekyll)</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Welcome to my wholly reworked website! This time, I've dropped the complexity of Wordpress and opted for something significantly simpler: &lt;del>Jekyll&lt;/del> Hugo and GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having now hosted the site in GitHub Pages, here was the process I started with Hugo:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Created the Github Pages repo (rterakedis.github.io) -- this is where github pages looks for the blog's generated site files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created a 2nd Github repo: rterakedis.github.io.hugo -- this repo holds the source files for Hugo to parse and generate the site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added the GH Pages repo (rterakedis.github.io) as a submodule for rterakedis.github.io.hugo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edited the config.toml in the hugo files to include the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>baseURL = &amp;quot;https://blog.euc-rt.me/&amp;quot;&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>publishdir = &amp;quot;rterakedis.github.io&amp;quot;&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add the CNAME file into the rterakedis.github.io repo and enable the custom name/https in the repo settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure the output from &lt;code>hugo&lt;/code> builds into the rterakedis.github.io directory in my local rterakedis.github.io.hugo directory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Commit and push everything to GitHub&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>A few quick links that I found particularly helpful when I was working with Jekyll:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>