<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn-Something-New on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/categories/learn-something-new/</link><description>Recent content in Learn-Something-New on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 21:54:25 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/categories/learn-something-new/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ensuring Domain Name Survival</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/ensuring-domain-name-survival/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 21:54:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/ensuring-domain-name-survival/</guid><description>
I was listening to the Security Now Podcast the other day, and a GREAT topic came up that I wanted to write about. That topic, as covered by Leo and Steve, involves ownership (specifically registrants) of Domain Name System (DNS) records. I know from past experience, domain &amp;quot;ownership&amp;quot; never seems to be front-of-mind for many folks deciding to start a website. Whether you're simply looking to blog, or starting a new business, the focus tends to be on the outcome (&amp;quot;I have a new website&amp;quot;) than the path to get there.</description></item><item><title>Great *Free* Resources to Learn GitHub</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/great-free-resources-to-learn-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/great-free-resources-to-learn-github/</guid><description>
Background Source control used to be a scary, odd thing for me back in college and early in my career. Branching, merging, commits... all the buzzwords I remember from my early days dealing with Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS) and Subversion. Admittedly, I never felt like I spent the time required to understand how it all worked. Fast forward to mid-2017, when a group of us within VMware needed to share some of our tips and tricks with the broader VMware community.</description></item></channel></rss>