<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workspace ONE on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/workspace-one/</link><description>Recent content in Workspace ONE on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/workspace-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Practices for Apple Admins in Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/best-practices-for-apple-admins-in-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/best-practices-for-apple-admins-in-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>I was recently reading a post about What to do when you have to lay off your Jamf administrator, and it got me thinking. The Workspace ONE UEM documentation generally specifies what you need from a software and hardware perspective in pre-requisites. That said, over the years I've come to know a few unwritten (or written but obscure) best practices for setting up Workspace ONE UEM to manage Apple devices. Hopefully you find this post helpful, but I welcome any comments and feedback!</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting macOS Management with Workspace ONE</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/troubleshooting-macos-management-with-workspace-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/troubleshooting-macos-management-with-workspace-one/</guid><description>Short post today - just to cover some thoughts on my most recent asset published to TechZone. I finally sat down and dug out all my notes on troubleshooting macOS and put them all together into a single, comprehensive macOS Troubleshooting Guide. This thing was the result of almost 46 hours of fingers on keys: typing, formatting, and testing. I truly hope you all get some value out of it, and do feel free to send me feedback if you'd like it extended and/or notice something missing.</description></item><item><title>Building a Basic Azure HomeLab for Testing Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/2020-08-09-building-basic-azure-homelab-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/2020-08-09-building-basic-azure-homelab-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>NOTE: This is still under construction but I wanted to share what I had so far...
Two things intersected for me this weekend: Issues with my current lab setup, and realization of some unused credits with my MSDN subscription. This led me down the path of building a basic Azure homelab for Workspace ONE UEM testing. My intent of this blog post is to document the process for myself to re-use, but I also invite your comments on how to improve the scenario.</description></item></channel></rss>