<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Key Added to SoftwareUpdate Command in macOS</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/new-key-added-softwareupdate-command-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/new-key-added-softwareupdate-command-macos/</guid><description>When Big Sur released, I noticed an issue trying to discover what macOS versions were available in SoftwareUpdate. I worked around this by using the installinstallmacos.py script to download full installers from the store. This script/tool is solid, but I was really hoping to be able to just do the updates using softwareupdate. Awhile back I filed feedback with Apple to the following:
The &amp;ndash;fetch-full-installer parameter for the softwareupdate command line tool is awesome, but there&amp;rsquo;s currently no way to discover the list of available values for the &amp;ndash;full-installer-version parameter.</description></item><item><title>Converting Jamf Custom Schema JSON for Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/converting-jamf-custom-schema-json-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/converting-jamf-custom-schema-json-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>Periodically, I see app vendors providing custom JSON schema files to help build app-specific configuration profiles for MDM (specifically Jamf). Workspace ONE UEM supports app-specific configuration, but currently via Custom Settings in an XML format. While many vendors also suppply a custom mobileconfig file or Custom Settings dictionary that can be used with Workspace ONE UEM, I hope in this post to show how any Workspace ONE admin can manually convert a Custom Schema JSON file to Custom Settings XML.</description></item><item><title>Updated GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/updated-github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</guid><description>When I restarted my blogging journey last year, I went with Hugo to generate a static website hosted as a GitHub Pages site. As mentioned, Blogger and WordPress always suffered recurring problems, and maintenance with WordPress still turned into a time suck due to its complexity. By comparison, GitHub has been a nearly painless hosting provider, and the way I&amp;rsquo;ve configured it has allowed me to keep drafts hidden by staging in a private repository.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting macOS Management with Workspace ONE</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/troubleshooting-macos-management-with-workspace-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/troubleshooting-macos-management-with-workspace-one/</guid><description>Short post today - just to cover some thoughts on my most recent asset published to TechZone. I finally sat down and dug out all my notes on troubleshooting macOS and put them all together into a single, comprehensive macOS Troubleshooting Guide. This thing was the result of almost 46 hours of fingers on keys: typing, formatting, and testing. I truly hope you all get some value out of it, and do feel free to send me feedback if you&amp;rsquo;d like it extended and/or notice something missing.</description></item><item><title>Deploying NoMAD over VMware Per-App Tunnel</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/deploying-nomad-over-vmware-per-app-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/deploying-nomad-over-vmware-per-app-tunnel/</guid><description>Some folks recently reached out to me asking for help figuring out how to route NoMAD traffic over VMware Tunnel. Basically, the ask was to use Per-App Tunneling to give NoMAD the ability to obtain Kerberos Tickets and Sync AD passwords without being directly on the Enterprise network. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with my previous article about the macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO Plugin, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that Apple&amp;rsquo;s built-in functionality in Catalina doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with Per-App Tunneling.</description></item><item><title>Modify ZShell Defaults in macOS</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/modify-zshell-defaults/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/modify-zshell-defaults/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself using the Terminal quite a bit more in my job. I spent a few minutes over the past few days looking at different ways to make the default terminal layout in macOS better. While there are many plugins out there for doing this (Oh-My-Zsh), I wanted to do something a little more straightforward.
How You Change zsh Default Layouts Armin Briegel has a great article about customizing the zsh prompt in his moving to zsh series.</description></item><item><title>macOS Big Sur and Kerberos SSO via Per-App Tunnel</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/macos-bigsur-kerberos-sso-over-vpn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/macos-bigsur-kerberos-sso-over-vpn/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my blogs about macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO over Per-App Tunnel and the followup, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that this has been a use-case I&amp;rsquo;m interested in solving. I put a great deal of effort into filing feedback with Apple and providing steps to replicate the issue. I was quite excited when I saw the per-app Tunnel improvements specifically mentioned in the WWDC videos, and hoped perhaps some changes were made to enable this functionality.</description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/github-actions-publish-private-hugo-repo-to-public-pages-site/</guid><description>I restarted my blogging journey earlier this year when I started looking into Jekyll Hugo to generate a static website. I had past experience with Blogger and Wordpress, but frankly had periodic problems with both platforms that ended up being a time suck. As it has been, Hugo has been a simplistic publishing method and GitHub a reliable (and FREE) hosting provider. Yet, my desire to keep my drafts private (.</description></item><item><title>Building a Basic Azure HomeLab for Testing Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/2020-08-09-building-basic-azure-homelab-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/2020-08-09-building-basic-azure-homelab-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>NOTE: This is still under construction but I wanted to share what I had so far&amp;hellip;
Two things intersected for me this weekend: Issues with my current lab setup, and realization of some unused credits with my MSDN subscription. This led me down the path of building a basic Azure homelab for Workspace ONE UEM testing. My intent of this blog post is to document the process for myself to re-use, but I also invite your comments on how to improve the scenario.</description></item><item><title>macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO over VPN Followup</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn-followup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn-followup/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going back and forth with Apple about some of the issues I previously found using the macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO over Per-App VPN. As it turns out, they acknowledged some of the issues I was seeing and are supposedly working on a fix. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching the past few beta releases for macOS, and I&amp;rsquo;ve not yet seen anything in the release notes to indicate they&amp;rsquo;ve implemented any fixes.</description></item><item><title>My Adapted Digital Bullet Journal via iPad Pro and GoodNotes 5</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-03-06-organizing-adapted-digital-bullet-journal-ipad-goodnotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-03-06-organizing-adapted-digital-bullet-journal-ipad-goodnotes/</guid><description>Background Last year, my wife introduced me to an entirely foreign-to-me concept of journaling known as Bullet Journaling. For those of you uninitiated, think of bullet journaling as an extensible planner with a heavy focus on the index to help bring order to chaos. A bullet journal is flexible, allowing you to organize tasks, events, collections (groups of tasks, ideas, and more). Bullet Journaling was born of a need to bring all the ideas/tasks/events plaguing us in the digital age and put them to paper in a single place.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Microsoft Defender ATP for macOS using Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-18-Deploying-Microsoft-ATP-Defender-for-Mac-using-Workspace-One/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-18-Deploying-Microsoft-ATP-Defender-for-Mac-using-Workspace-One/</guid><description>I had a few folks recently approach me on the MacAdmins slack asking for help with deploying Microsoft Defender ATP for Mac. We got it working, but it came down to 2 issues: conflicting documentation and Jamf/inTune specific templates. Once I was able to parse through the Jamf/InTune documentation, we were able to put together some guidance. We recently published this guide to the EUC Samples GitHub Repository.
Conflicting Documentation The initial problem I found was some confusion generated by Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s documentation.</description></item><item><title>Testing macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO Extension Over VPN</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macOS-Catalina-Kerberos-SSO-Over-VPN/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macOS-Catalina-Kerberos-SSO-Over-VPN/</guid><description>Working at VMware, I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by great technology and super-smart folks! In our portfolio of technologies, the folks in our R&amp;amp;D have recently been putting quite a bit of effort into building out macOS capabilities for our Workspace ONE Tunnel client for macOS. Workspace ONE admins can leverage the same VMware technology they used to enable per-app VPN for iOS and Android, but now on macOS! There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of nuance to configuring the VPN client if you&amp;rsquo;re previously familiar with iOS (look for my Operational Tutorial soon to hit TechZone).</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Hugo (from Jekyll)</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</guid><description>Welcome to my wholly reworked website! This time, I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped the complexity of Wordpress and opted for something significantly simpler: Jekyll Hugo and GitHub.
Having now hosted the site in GitHub Pages, here was the process I started with Hugo:
Created the Github Pages repo (rterakedis.github.io) &amp;ndash; this is where github pages looks for the blog&amp;rsquo;s generated site files. Created a 2nd Github repo: rterakedis.github.io.hugo &amp;ndash; this repo holds the source files for Hugo to parse and generate the site.</description></item></channel></rss>