<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Robert&#39;s Flummox Capacitor</title>
    <link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Robert&#39;s Flummox Capacitor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Adapted Digital Bullet Journal via iPad Pro and GoodNotes 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-03-06-organizing-adapted-digital-bullet-journal-ipad-goodnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-03-06-organizing-adapted-digital-bullet-journal-ipad-goodnotes/</guid>
      <description>Background Last year, my wife introduced me to an entirely foreign-to-me concept of journaling known as Bullet Journaling. For those of you uninitiated, think of bullet journaling as an extensible planner with a heavy focus on the index to help bring order to chaos. A bullet journal is flexible, allowing you to organize tasks, events, collections (groups of tasks, ideas, and more). Bullet Journaling was born of a need to bring all the ideas/tasks/events plaguing us in the digital age and put them to paper in a single place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Microsoft Defender ATP for macOS using Workspace ONE UEM</title>
      <link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-18-deploying-microsoft-atp-defender-for-mac-using-workspace-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-18-deploying-microsoft-atp-defender-for-mac-using-workspace-one/</guid>
      <description>I had a few folks recently approach me on the MacAdmins slack asking for help with deploying Microsoft Defender ATP for Mac. We got it working, but it came down to 2 issues: conflicting documentation and Jamf/inTune specific templates. Once I was able to parse through the Jamf/InTune documentation, we were able to put together some guidance. We recently published this guide to the EUC Samples GitHub Repository.
Conflicting Documentation The initial problem I found was some confusion generated by Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing macOS Catalina Kerberos SSO Extension Over VPN</title>
      <link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2020-02-04-macos-catalina-kerberos-sso-over-vpn/</guid>
      <description>Working at VMware, I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by great technology and super-smart folks! In our portfolio of technologies, the folks in our R&amp;amp;D have recently been putting quite a bit of effort into building out macOS capabilities for our Workspace ONE Tunnel client for macOS. Workspace ONE admins can leverage the same VMware technology they used to enable per-app VPN for iOS and Android, but now on macOS! There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of nuance to configuring the VPN client if you&amp;rsquo;re previously familiar with iOS (look for my Operational Tutorial soon to hit TechZone).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Hugo (from Jekyll)</title>
      <link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/2018-06-15-welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my wholly reworked website! This time, I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped the complexity of Wordpress and opted for something significantly simpler: Jekyll Hugo and GitHub.
Having now hosted the site in GitHub Pages, here was the process I started with Hugo:
 Created the Github Pages repo (rterakedis.github.io) &amp;ndash; this is where github pages looks for the blog&amp;rsquo;s generated site files. Created a 2nd Github repo: rterakedis.github.io.hugo &amp;ndash; this repo holds the source files for Hugo to parse and generate the site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>