<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/about/</guid><description>My name is Robert Terakedis. I'm a Microsoft-based datacenter engineer turned Senior Technical Marketing Architect at VMware turned Product Architect at OneTrust.
More specifically, I've been in the Tech industry since 2002. I've held various roles spanning Microsoft-platform datacenter support and engineering (Exchange, Hyper-V infrastructure, Citrix, etc). In 2014, I moved into a new role dealing with Apple device management in the Enterprise. In 2022, I switched gears again and started as a Product Architect at OneTrust.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Apple Device Management</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/gettingstarted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/gettingstarted/</guid><description>One of the most common questions I get is where a device administrator can get started learning about Apple device management with Workspace ONE. This is not an exhaustive list, but I did hope to help point you to some great resources:
Understanding MDM Protocol Apple's MDM protocol is the foundation on which every MDM/EMM vendor relies. You'll be far more effective at troubleshooting the more you understand this protocol, and how it works.</description></item><item><title>Sticker Templates</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/stickers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/stickers/</guid><description>Stickers As it so happens, I found a fun new hobby creating stickers in ProCreate on my iPad Pro with the 2nd Gen Apple Pencil. Hopefully you enjoy these -- if you decide to print any as stickers, be sure to send me one!</description></item></channel></rss>