<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 22:28:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HomePod Mini Ignoring Family Explicit Content Settings and Simply Not Working</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/homepod-mini-ignoring-family-explicit-content-settings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 22:28:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/homepod-mini-ignoring-family-explicit-content-settings/</guid><description>
Sudden panic set in as I walked by my child's room and heard the lyric from Monsters by All Time Low -- &amp;quot;I don't mind while you f**k up my life&amp;quot;
Yes, I just had the realization that the critical parental controls on the Homepod Mini's in my children's rooms were no longer working as intended. This set off a multi-hour troubleshooting session, with some involvement from AppleCare, that got things working until it didn't (again).</description></item><item><title>Apple's Missing Hardware - A KVM Switch</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/apples-missing-hardware-kvm-switch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 15:40:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/apples-missing-hardware-kvm-switch/</guid><description>
Let me start by saying that I'm assuming many of you out there are in a situation quite similar to my own. This situation; having a personal Mac and a work Mac (and maybe an iPad Pro thrown into that mix also). But if you're also like me, you have limited space on your desk and don't want to be surrounded by monitors! This leads me to my most potent complaint about Apple hardware; the lack of a KVM switch.</description></item><item><title>Best Practices for Apple Admins in Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/best-practices-for-apple-admins-in-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/best-practices-for-apple-admins-in-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>
Background I was recently reading a post about What to do when you have to lay off your Jamf administrator, and it got me thinking. The Workspace ONE UEM documentation generally specifies what you need from a software and hardware perspective in pre-requisites. That said, over the years I've come to know a few unwritten (or written but obscure) best practices for setting up Workspace ONE UEM to manage Apple devices.</description></item><item><title>Converting Jamf Custom Schema JSON for Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/converting-jamf-custom-schema-json-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/converting-jamf-custom-schema-json-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>
Background Periodically, I see app vendors providing custom JSON schema files to help build app-specific configuration profiles for MDM (specifically Jamf). Workspace ONE UEM supports app-specific configuration, but currently via Custom Settings in an XML format. While many vendors also suppply a custom mobileconfig file or Custom Settings dictionary that can be used with Workspace ONE UEM, I hope in this post to show how any Workspace ONE admin can manually convert a Custom Schema JSON file to Custom Settings XML.</description></item><item><title>Modify ZShell Defaults in macOS</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/modify-zshell-defaults/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/modify-zshell-defaults/</guid><description>
Background I'm finding myself using the Terminal quite a bit more in my job. I spent a few minutes over the past few days looking at different ways to make the default terminal layout in macOS better. While there are many plugins out there for doing this (Oh-My-Zsh), I wanted to do something a little more straightforward.
How You Change zsh Default Layouts Armin Briegel has a great article about customizing the zsh prompt in his moving to zsh series.</description></item></channel></rss>