<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apple on Robert Terakedis</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in apple on Robert Terakedis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Robert Terakedis; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euc-rt.me/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Practices for Apple Admins in Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/best-practices-for-apple-admins-in-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/best-practices-for-apple-admins-in-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>I was recently reading a post about What to do when you have to lay off your Jamf administrator, and it got me thinking. The Workspace ONE UEM documentation generally specifies what you need from a software and hardware perspective in pre-requisites. That said, over the years I've come to know a few unwritten (or written but obscure) best practices for setting up Workspace ONE UEM to manage Apple devices. Hopefully you find this post helpful, but I welcome any comments and feedback!</description></item><item><title>Converting Jamf Custom Schema JSON for Workspace ONE UEM</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/converting-jamf-custom-schema-json-workspace-one-uem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/converting-jamf-custom-schema-json-workspace-one-uem/</guid><description>Periodically, I see app vendors providing custom JSON schema files to help build app-specific configuration profiles for MDM (specifically Jamf). Workspace ONE UEM supports app-specific configuration, but currently via Custom Settings in an XML format. While many vendors also suppply a custom mobileconfig file or Custom Settings dictionary that can be used with Workspace ONE UEM, I hope in this post to show how any Workspace ONE admin can manually convert a Custom Schema JSON file to Custom Settings XML.</description></item><item><title>Modify ZShell Defaults in macOS</title><link>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/modify-zshell-defaults/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euc-rt.me/post/modify-zshell-defaults/</guid><description>I'm finding myself using the Terminal quite a bit more in my job. I spent a few minutes over the past few days looking at different ways to make the default terminal layout in macOS better. While there are many plugins out there for doing this (Oh-My-Zsh), I wanted to do something a little more straightforward.
How You Change zsh Default Layouts Armin Briegel has a great article about customizing the zsh prompt in his moving to zsh series.</description></item></channel></rss>